Working with the amount fields in
Business Central.
When you work with amount fields on
journals and documents, you type in
amounts in the same field regardless if
the amount is a debit or credit amount.
You use a sign in front of the amount to
determine if the amount is debit or
credit
depending on the scenario.
And by default, an amount and amount and
local currency field is shown.
If you're more comfortable working with
a debit and credit amounts specifically,
maybe you think it gives a better
overview,
you can change the setting to reveal
these two fields and the local currency
counterparts. This is done at the
general ledger setup page. Let's go
there.
I bring up the tell me search with Alt
Q.
I type general ledger setup
and I select search result.
To find the field I'm looking for, I
want to expand to see the full list of
fields on the general fast tab. So, I
click the show more link on the right
side.
I browse down to find the show amounts
field.
Here I can select different options. In
my case, I'd like to work with the debit
and credit fields, so I select debit and
credit only.
Now, when I go to, for example, the
general journal,
let's go there.
And I browse out to the right
and find my amount fields.
Now, I find that the debit amount and
credit amount field has been revealed
here.
In my case, I like this because it gives
me an overview of when things balance
and they don't.
This is up to your preference, but
notice that when you change this
setting, it applies company-wide and not
only for the current user. It applies
for all users.
This way, you can determine which kind
of amount fields to work with.
Thank you for watching.